Tigers will come back.
So let's continue with our discussion on the integration management as I mentioned in the last video
it's all about bringing together all the resources for the project delivery and to name a few elements
we have to handle the social location balancing competing demands examining project delivery approaches
like a giant waterfall over delver managing the inter-dependence.
So let's say that this system depends on some other system and they are also working through a separate
project and there is a separate project manager.
So we need to work with that project manager with that team to ensure that that project is delivered
at the same time so that we can proceed ahead with our work.
Let's say we depend on that software for functioning so unless until that software is available we cannot
test our systems.
So it's very important to work on these interdependencies.
And then these are the management processes integration management processes.
The first one is develop project charter.
Then we have to develop the project management plan direct and manage project work manage project knowledge
perform integrate the change and to close the project or freeze so you can see that all these six integration
processes are covering the project from the beginning.
And so we have fun is developing project charter and then we are closing the project with the last point
here.
So we will address all of them.
And the objective of integration management is to ensure that our genome project is delivered well.
Everything is well aligned.
We have a project management plan we have and we are working on creating a knowledge repository because
it's very important to maintain the knowledge documentation in organization.
Most of these projects are kind of routine and you me get you know similar changes in the future.
Even if 100 person project is not same at least there are a lot of elements which are Colman's or at
least you can go back and forth to these documents that will see a lot of effort and lot of cost.
Then we have maintaining the project management plan making integrated decision for project and completing
and closing the project.
These are some of the very important points which are considered to like use of automated tools.
So you may use tools like Jeta.
I speak will decontrol software.
There are a lot of software in the market which are used so you can use these tools you can use visual
management tools prod and project knowledge management expanding the project managers sponsible.
These are opting for hybrid methodologies and these are probably the factors which are critical in the
selection of a project is implemented how all of these activities are implemented.
So we have project lifecycle development lifecycle management approaches knowledge management change
governance lesson learned and benefits.
So these are a very important point which are impacting the integration management.
How all of these elements are handled in a company in the organization decides how we are going to deliver
a project.
So that's it for now.
We will continue and talk more about these individual processes in the upcoming videos.
Thank you.